💌 cristianmsbr@gmail.com | 🏕 crhenr.xyz | 🖸 crhenr | 🛅 crhenr | 🐚 crhenr | 🎓 Cristian Souza | Lattes CV

Summary_

Currently studying Computer Systems Networking at IFRN, Brazil. Experienced in information security, system administration, computer vision, and image processing. Works on research projects since high school. Likes trying new tools and technologies, as well as developing new open-source projects to help the community.

Experience _____

Actions Security Remote

Information Security Analyst

May 2018 - Jul. 2019

- Main programming languages: Python and C.
- Contributed to the development of a Web Application Firewall (WAF).
- Worked with the Elastic Stack, Docker containers and reverse proxies.
- Implanted an OpenStack infrastructure.
- Executed penetration tests in web applications.
- · Other technologies: ModSecurity, Linux.

Federal Institute of Rio Grande do Norte

Natal, RN - Brazil

Apr. 2016 - Dec. 2018

R&D SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- · Main programming languages: Java and Python.
- · Worked in the fields of computer vision and image processing.
- Developed an ALPR application for embedded hardware (with patent application).
- Developed an OCR application.
- Developed a deep learning face recognition application and API.
- Other technologies: OpenCV, dlib, REST, Flask, MySQL, RFID.

Education

IFRN (Federal Institute of Rio Grande do Norte)

Natal, RN - Brazil

Computer Systems Networking Degree

2019 - Now

IMD (Digital Metropolis Institute)

Natal, RN - Brazil

CERTIFICATE PROGRAM IN ELECTRONICS

2018 - 2019

IFRN (Federal Institute of Rio Grande do Norte)

Natal, RN - Brazil

CERTIFICATE PROGRAM IN INFORMATICS

2015 - 2018

Skills

Languages Portuguese (native), English (advanced level), French (basic level)

Programming C, Java, Python, Shell Script, SQL

Generic AWS, Penetration Testing, Git, Docker, Elastic Stack, Linux Administration, Flask, REST

Certifications _____

Linux+, CompTIA

9BSTQ4TM5LEE1GKT

LPIC-1, Linux Professional Institute

LPI000393801

Research Papers _____

On detecting and mitigating phishing attacks through featureless machine learning techniques

DOI: 10.1002/itl2.135

WILEY INTERNET TECHNOLOGY LETTERS

2020

• Cristian Henrique M. Souza, Marcilio O. O. Lemos, Felipe S. Dantas Silva, Robinson L. Souza Alves

August 21, 2020 Cristian Souza · Resume

PhishKiller: Uma Ferramenta para Detecção e Mitigação de Ataques de Phishing Através de Técnicas de Deep Learning

SBSeg 2019

XIX SIMPÓSIO BRASILEIRO DE SEGURANÇA DA INFORMAÇÃO E DE SISTEMAS COMPUTACIONAIS

• Cristian Henrique M. Souza, Marcilio O. O. Lemos, Felipe S. Dantas Silva, Robinson Luis S. Alves

DOI: 10.1007/978-3-030-02683-7_62

Embedded System for Access Control Based on Facial Biometry and RFID PROCEEDINGS OF THE FUTURE TECHNOLOGIES CONFERENCE

PROCEEDINGS OF THE FUTURE TECHNOLOGIES CONFERENCE • Cristian Henrique M. Souza, Ivanilson França V. Júnior, Robinson Luis S. Alves, Arthur Henrique C. Costa, Melquiad	2018 des P. Lima Júnior
Honors & Awards	
CVE-2019-7634, Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures Capture the Wave Champion, Darkwaves Conference	2019 2018
Open-source Projects	
Freki	
MALWARE ANALYSIS PLATFORM • Features: static analysis, user management, REST API, and Web UI.	Python
OpenBSD self-hosted DEPLOY PRIVATE SERVICES ON TOP OF OPENBSD • Features: automatically installs and configures cloud, git, and email services.	Shell Script
JCEditor	
• Features: syntax-highlighting, cross-platform, Swing UI.	Java
Patents & Software	
Sistema Embarcado para Reconhecimento Automático de Placas de Veículos	2018
BR 10 2018 015493 1	
NAVI RPi Face Recognition	2019
BR512019000143-5	
NAVI-ALPR	2019
BR512019000144-3	
NAVI Face Recognition API	2019
BR512019000141-9	

Sistema Embarcado para Medição de Pluviosidade e Gerenciamento SNMP

2019

2018

BR512018000086-0

OCR-NAVI

BR512019000140-0